liveatc.net 2019-06-18

# Privacy Policy | LiveATC.net

LiveATC.net recognizes that your privacy is very important - we have always taken it seriously, and will continue to do so. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. 

**What This Privacy Policy Covers**

This policy covers how LiveATC.net treats personal information that LiveATC.net might collect and receive, including information related to your past use of LiveATC.net products and services. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that LiveATC.net does not own or control, or to people that LiveATC.net does not employ or manage. 

**Information Collection and Use**

**Who is the Data Controller?**

LiveATC.net is the **_“data controller”_** of personal data collected by LiveATC.net and is responsible for deciding how personal data is collected, used, and disclosed. 

You should be aware that when you provide information to us using a third-party site or platform, the information you provide may be separately collected by the third-party site or platform. The information we collect is covered by the LiveATC Privacy Policy only, and the information the third-party site or platform collects is subject to the third-party site or platform’s privacy practices. Privacy choices you have made on the third-party site or platform will not apply to our use of the information we have collected directly through our Site or Services. Please also keep in mind that our Site and Services may contain links to other sites not owned or controlled by us and we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Site or Services and to read the policies of other sites that may collect your personal information. 

**General**

LiveATC.net may collect personal information when you register with LiveATC.net, when you use LiveATC.net products or services, when you visit LiveATC.net pages or the pages of certain LiveATC.net partners. LiveATC.net may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies. When you register with us we may ask for information such as your name, email address, birth date, address, and any other information relevant to the purpose of a particular transaction. Once you register with LiveATC.net and sign-in to our services, you are not anonymous to us. LiveATC.net collects information about your transactions with us. LiveATC.net may also ask you for credit card information to process your transactions with us, or to verify your identity or age. 

LiveATC.net automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, LiveATC.net cookie information, and the page/s and products you request. 

LiveATC.net uses information for the following general purposes: to customize the advertising and content you see, fulfill your requests for products and services, improve our services, contact you if you grant us permission to, conduct research, and for internal reporting purposes. 

**Your controls and choices**

The laws in some jurisdictions requires us to provide you the ability to exercise certain controls and choices regarding our collection, use and sharing of your information. To the extent those laws apply to you, your controls and choices may include: 

\- Updating, and deleting your registration account;   
\- Choosing or changing your choices for subscriptions, newsletters, and alerts;   
\- Choosing whether to receive from us offers and promotions for our products and services, or products and services that we think may be of interest to you;   
\- Choosing whether we share your personal information with other companies so they can send you offers and promotions about their products and services;   
\- Controlling targeted advertising from many ad networks and partners; data exchanges; and marketing analytics and digital advertising and marketing service providers (by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance);   
\- Controlling whether you want us to access location information, such as by controlling or disabling location services in your mobile device’s settings menu;   
\- Choosing to control targeted advertising you receive within applications by using the settings and choices made available to you through your device(s), for example, by re-setting your device’s advertising identifier and/or opting out of interest based ads;   
\- Requesting removal of your personal information from a public forum on one of our sites or application. 

**Children**

When a child under age 13 attempts to register with the LiveATC.net Forums, we ask that he or she have a parent or guardian grant parental permission. LiveATC.net will not contact children under age 13 about special offers or for marketing purposes without a parent's permission. LiveATC.net does not ask a child under age 13 for more personal information, as a condition of participation, than is reasonably necessary to participate in a given activity or promotion. Please see our Notice to Parents Regarding the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 below for more details. 

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

LiveATC.net does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services you have requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances: 

We provide the information to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with LiveATC.net under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your personal information to help LiveATC.net communicate with you about offers from LiveATC.net and our marketing partners. However, unless you have granted permission, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information. 

We have a parent's permission to share the information if the user is a child under age 13. Parents have the option of allowing LiveATC.net to collect and use their child's information without consenting to LiveATC.net sharing of this information with people and companies who may use this information for their own purposes; 

We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; 

We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of LiveATC.net's Terms and Conditions of Use, or as otherwise required by law. 

We will transfer information about you if LiveATC.net is acquired by or merged with another company. We will post a notice on our site before this occurs and/or if a new privacy policy will be applicable as a result. 

LiveATC.net works with vendors, partners, advertisers, and other service providers. In order to bring you the products and services you have requested, we may share your personal information with them. We will not authorize these service providers to share your information other than as necessary to provide the services you have requested or beyond the extent to which you have granted us permission to do so. 

LiveATC.net may display targeted advertisements based on personal information. 

**Cookies, Web Beacons, and Shared Objects**

LiveATC.net may set and access cookies on your computer. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a website to the hard drive of your computer so that the site administrator may identify your computer and passively track its activities on the website. This unique number identifies your web browser to our computer system. A cookie will not allow a website to learn any personally identifiable information (such as your real name and address) that you have not otherwise disclosed. Cookies allow us to automatically remember your web browser when you visit our site or Service. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and they are currently used on most major websites. It is possible to adjust your Web browser preferences to alert you when a cookie is sent to your hard drive, or to refuse cookies altogether. While we do not require you to use cookies, keep in mind that certain sites and services will not function properly if you set your browser to refuse all cookies. 

Web beacons, also known as clear GIFs or single-pixel GIFs, are small image files that we may place on Web pages and within certain email. Working in conjunction with cookies, Web beacons allow us to accurately count the number of unique users who have visited a specific page and the number of times those pages are displayed. We can also use Web beacons to let us know how many people opened certain types of email. This information is only collected in aggregate form and will not be linked to your personally identifiable information. Keep in mind that any image file on a Web page can act as a Web beacon. Third-party advertisers may use Web beacons in their advertisements. 

Shared Objects are used to store data on your computer in much the same way that data is stored in a cookie created through a web browser. Various uses of Shared Objects include remembering a user's favorite color, or the last frame of a movie watched. The data can only be read by movies originating from the same domain that created the Shared Object. Shared Objects can not remember a user's e-mail address or other personal information unless they willingly provide such information. 

Without cookies, Web beacons, and Shared Objects, it would be difficult for us to know which services have a larger audience than others, or to offer you all the services and functionality that we do. Tracking audience size helps us to better understand when to launch new services and enhance the current offerings. 

LiveATC.net lets other companies that show advertisements on some of our pages or offer you products and services in connection with the LiveATC.net Service set and access their cookies on your computer. Other companies' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Advertisers or other companies do not have access to LiveATC.net's cookies. 

We use both in-house and third-party ad serving technologies to help us deliver ads with some of the audio streams you listen to. Such technology may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visit to the website where you selected the audio stream in order to identify and display advertisements that may be of interest to you. In the course of serving these advertisements, a unique cookie may be placed or recognized on your browser. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used to serve ads to you, please [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) . 

**Your Ability to Edit and Delete Your Forum Account Information and Preferences**

**General**

You can edit your LiveATC.net Forum Account Information at any time. We reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to the LiveATC.net service, such as service announcements or administrative messages, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them. You can delete your LiveATC.net account by visiting our Forum page. 

**Children**

Parents can review, edit, and delete information relating to their child's LiveATC.net account using tools offered in the LiveATC.net Forums. If a parent chooses not to allow us to further collect or use a child's information, parents enrolled in LiveATC.net Forum Accounts can delete their child's account by signing into that child's account and requesting deletion. 

**Confidentiality and Security at LiveATC.net**

We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. 

We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that protect personal information about you. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

LiveATC.net may update this policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your LiveATC.net account or by placing a prominent notice on our site. 

NOTICE: [Click here](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/pubs/consumer/tech/tec13.shtm) for important information about safe surfing from the Federal Trade Commission. 

If you have questions or suggestions, you can contact us at: 

LiveATC.net LLC   
P.O. Box 178   
Amherst, NH 03031   
Or send an electronic message via the [site contact form](http://www.liveatc.net/ct/contact.php)

*NOTICE REGARDING CHILDREN'S ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT OF 1998 (COPPA)* 

LiveATC.net, in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) of 1998, provides notice to parents of children under 13 that: 

LiveATC.net may collect personal information about children under 13 years of age in order to provide them with access to services and content on the LiveATC.net Service; 

LiveATC.net needs the consent of parents or guardians to collect, use and disclose personally identifiable information about children under 13; 

LiveATC.net has created a mechanism by which parents and guardians can provide consent; and 

LiveATC.net may not require children under 13 to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity as a condition of participation. 

. A parent must provide consent in order for a child to register for the LiveATC.net Forums. 

**How to View or Change a Child's Information**

To view or change any of your child's information, including the child's password, log in to the child's LiveATC.net Forum account and view the account information. From there you can change the child's account information. We suggest that you include your child whenever you make changes to your child's membership. This will provide another opportunity to talk about safety on the Internet. 

**How to Delete a Child's Membership**

To delete a child's membership simply send an electronic message via the [site contact form](http://www.liveatc.net/ct/contact.php). Include the child's LiveATC.net Forum username, and ask that the child account be deleted. 

As a general matter, LiveATC.net encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the activities offered on the sites that they visit. No information should be submitted to or posted on the LiveATC.net Forums by visitors and registered users under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian. 

Correspondence: If your child contacts LiveATC.net, we may keep a record of that correspondence. We do not collect any e-mail addresses of those who communicate with LiveATC.net via e-mail. We use the information provided so that we may respond to the e-mail. LiveATC.net does not knowingly permit the registration of children under the age of 13 without the verifiable consent of their parents or guardians. 

As a general reminder: Children should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to anyone online. LiveATC.net does not knowingly share personal information about users under the age of 13 with third parties and we do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of age, without their permission. In addition, LiveATC.net will not send any direct e-mail offers to users who indicate they are under the age of 13. LiveATC.net strongly suggests that parents read the Online Bulletin, published by, and reprinted with the permission of, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children and that they make use of the Parental Controls available through the Internet and/or your web browser. 

If you have any questions about this Notice or about the collection or maintenance of your child's personal information anywhere on LiveATC.net, please contact: 

LiveATC.net LLC   
P.O. Box 178   
Amherst, NH 03031   
Or send an electronic message via the [site contact form](http://www.liveatc.net/ct/contact.php)

_Last update: May 22, 2018 - clarifications to comply with General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)_
